mymoneykarma.com 2019-04-19

# Privacy Policy Terms | MyMoneyKarma

Your privacy is important to us.

This policy covers how MyMoneyKarma Infomatics India Private Limited, a company with offices at T-Hub Foundation, Catalyst, IIIT – Hyd Campus, Gachibowli, Hyderabad – 500 032 and Plot No:56, Anupama Homes, Emerald Gardens, NanakramgudaGachibowli, 5Min from Wipro Circle., Nanakram Guda,Hyderabad, Telangana 500008. Telangana treats personal information that we collect / receive / retain.

MyMoneyKarma's privacy policy is governed by one fundamental principle - maintain your trust and confidence when handling your personal information

* What Information Do We Collect

We collect two types of online information: non-personal and personal.

  1. Non-Personal Information

This information helps us provide an online experience that matches your device and to manage our online advertising.

    1. When you visit digital properties we own / control (e.g. our website, mobile app etc), we typically collect the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet, information such as what browser, browser version, operating system you have, the website you came from or the advertisement you viewed or clicked on.
    2. When you browse the MyMoneyKarma website, view our emails/SMS, use your mobile site/app, MyMoneyKarma or the companies we work with, use cookies and/or pixel tags to collect information and store your online preferences. Cookies are widely used and most browsers are set up to accept them automatically. If you would prefer, you can choose to not accept cookies. It's important to note that cookies and pixel tags do not capture any information that can personally identify you.
    3. We may also supplement the information we collect with information we receive from other companies. For example, we may use marketing segments developed by us or other companies to customize certain services
  2. Personal Information

In addition to the information described in the previous section, we may also gather personal information that you explicitly provide and share with us - such as your name, address, phone number, and email address. Collecting this personal information enables us to offer you a digital experience that will help us to deliver our services to you.. For example, we collect personal information when you:

    1. Register / Apply for our services
    2. Applying for a new product /service from us or from our lender partners

* How do we collect this information

We collect non-personal information on our owned properties (MyMoneyKarma website, mobile app etc) and from third parties. There are certain industry standard technologies we use to collect usage Information. In the future, other new technology and methods for collecting Usage Information may develop.

  1. Embedded Scripts.

An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Services, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your Device from our web server or a third party service provider, is active only while you are connected to the Services, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

  2. Web Beacons.

Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons (also known as "1x1 GIFs" or "clear GIFs") may be included in our web and mobile pages and messages. Web beacons may be invisible to you, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a web or mobile page or e-mail can act as a web beacon. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count users of the Services, to monitor how users navigate the Services, to count how many e-mails that were sent were actually opened or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie web beacons to Personal Information. We use a third-party tracking service that uses cookies to track non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our site

  3. Cookies

You can control whether to accept cookies or not. If you decide to not accept cookies, some features and services on our site may not work properly because we may not be able to recognize and associate you. In addition, the offers we provide when you visit us may not be as relevant to you or tailored to your interests. If you would prefer not to accept cookies, you can:

    1. Change your browser settings to notify you when you receive a cookie, which lets you choose whether or not to accept it
    2. Set your browser to automatically not accept any cookies
  4. Targeted Advertising

Like most advertisers, we place advertisements where we think they will be most relevant to customers. We believe that online behavioral advertising helps to provide you with more relevant advertising based upon on the websites you visit. We place advertisements by developing and using our own customer segmentation methodologies that may combine online and offline information about our current and prospective customers. In addition, we may use marketing segments provided by online publishers and network advertising companies.

We contract with third-party advertising networks, publishers and other entities to advertise our products and services on websites not affiliated with us. Network advertising companies that provide these services have their own privacy policies and are not subject to our Online Privacy Statement. Many of these companies provide ways to avoid targeted advertising provided by, or through them. Some of these ads are online behavioral advertising - which serve advertisements that are more likely to be of interest to you using non-personal behavioral information. Such ads may contain cookies that allow monitoring of websites (including our own websites that part of our own Services) and your response to our advertisements. Cookies placed by these companies do not collect Personal Information. We limit companies that place our ads from using information for any purpose other than to assist us in our advertising efforts.

  5. Do Not Track

Although there is no standard for how Do Not Track consumer browser settings should work on commercial websites, the industry has self-regulatory initiatives designed to provide consumers a choice in the types of ads they may see online and to conveniently opt-out from online behavioral ads served by some or all of the companies participating in these programs. Many of our advertising vendors and companies participate in these programs. Using the choice mechanisms these programs make available may help you see advertising that is relevant to you or help you avoid seeing interest based advertising generally. In order for behavioral advertising opt-outs to work on your device, your browser must be set to accept cookies. If you delete cookies, buy a new Device, access our Services from a different device, login under a different screen name, or change web browsers, you will need to opt-out again. If your browser has scripting disabled, you do not need to opt out, as online behavioral advertising technology does not work when scripting is disabled. Please check your browser's security settings to validate whether scripting is active or disabled.

  6. Information Third Parties Provide About You

We may supplement the information we collect about you with outside records from third parties in order to enhance our ability to serve you, to tailor our content to you and to offer you opportunities to purchase products or services that we believe may be of interest to you. We may combine the information we receive from those sources with information we collect through the Services. In those cases, we will apply this Privacy Policy to any Personal Information received, unless we have disclosed otherwise.

  7. Social media widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

  8. Third Party Content / Links To Third Party Services which appear on our website / digital properties

MyMoneyKarma may post links to third party web sites that are not subject to this privacy policy. We do not exercise control over the external sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices employed by any of these third parties. We encourage you to note when you leave our digital properties, that you read the privacy statements of all third party web sites or applications before submitting any Personal Information to third parties.

  9. Personal Information

We collect your personal information, including financial information, from the registration or other completed forms / questionnaires that you provide to us. We will also receive your personal information, including financial information, from documents that you may provide to us and/or from documents like the credit report that you authorise us to obtain on your behalf from Credit Information Companies. You will therefore know when we collect any personal information about you. We will collect your profile information based on your consent from digital and social media properties including but not limited to Facebook, Linkedin, Google etc.

* How do we use the Information that we collect?

We use the information about you that we collect for the following purposes:

  1. To provide you with the services you access on our website including but not limited to Free Credit health Check, Profiling Service etc.
  2. To provide you with the Services under the plan that you subscribe to
  3. To communicate with you for purposes related to the Services
  4. To personalize and improve our Services, including providing you with targeted advertising;
  5. To determine trends or metrics concerning how users are engaging with our online properties including our webpage;
  6. To provide lenders with information which enables them to process your loan/credit card application

* Can You Control Your Information That's Collected and Used Online?

It's important to note that the information we use about you helps us provide you with products, services and experiences that benefit you. You have the ability to control how your non-personal information is collected and used online.

You also have the ability to choose what personal information, including what sensitive personal information (i.e. your financial information) you provide to us. However, if you choose not to provide all of the information and data that is requested of you, we may not be able to provide you with the Services that you have subscribed to.You may, at any time while availing of our Services or otherwise, withdraw the consent given earlier to MyMoneyKarma to collect and use your sensitive personal data or information by writing to MyMoneyKarma at askus@mymoneykarma.com. However, in the case of you withdrawing such consent, MyMoneyKarma shall have the option to stop providing you the Services for which the information was sought. You will not be eligible for refund of any fees paid in such event.

When you provide your contact details, we will use it to send you general notices or important news about your account, request your feedback or opinions and provide updates on special deals and offers that might interest you.

We believe you should be able to choose what kinds of information you receive via email/SMS. If you do not want to receive marketing materials by email/SMS, just indicate your preference on the contact information for your account or the 'opt-out' link provided in our marketing emails. Please keep in mind that we will continue to notify you by email /SMS/via phone calls regarding your services with us.

You can review the information that you have provided to us by logging into your account at the MyMoneyKarma website and correct or amend any personal information or sensitive personal data or information to ensure that the information or data you provided us is accurate and/or not deficient. MyMoneyKarma is not responsible for the authenticity of any personal information or sensitive personal data or information supplied to it by you or any third party.

* How and When Do We Disclose Other Information To Third Parties?

We do not sell or rent your Personal Information to third parties for any purpose. We only share Personal Information when we have your express consent, or as otherwise provided for in this policy.

We may share with third parties certain pieces of aggregated, non-Personal Information, such as the number of users who clicked on a particular advertisement. Such information does not identify you individually.

  1. Third Parties Providing Services on Our Behalf

We may use third party vendors to perform certain aspects of the Services on our or your behalf, such as hosting the Services, designing and/or operating the Services' features, tracking the Services analytics or performing other administrative services. We may provide these vendors with access to user information, including Personal Information, to carry out the services they are performing for you or for us. However, we restrict the use of this information by such third party vendors in our agreement with them and require them to use the information only to provide their services to us.

  2. White-labelled/Co -Branded Services

Certain aspects of the Services may be provided to you in association with third parties such as our advertisers, business partners, or sponsors, and may require you to disclose Personal Information to them. Such Co-Branded Services will identify the third party. If you elect to register for products and/or services through the Co-Branded Services, you may be providing your information to both us and the third party. Any such information provided to the third party is subject to that third party's privacy policies. Further, if you sign-in to a Co-Branded Service with a username and password obtained through the Services, your Personal Information may be disclosed to the identified third parties for that Co-Branded Service and will be subject to their posted privacy policies.

  3. Administrative and Legal Reasons

We may access, use, preserve, transfer and disclose your information (including Personal Information, including disclosure to third parties: (i) to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, subpoenas, governmental requests or legal process if in our good faith opinion such is required or permitted by law; (ii) to protect and/or defend the Terms of Use for any of our Services or other policies applicable to any of our Services, including investigation of potential violations thereof; (iii) to protect the safety, rights, property or security of the Services or any third party; and/or (iv) to detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues. Further, we may use IP addresses or other Device Identifiers, to identify users, and may do so in cooperation with third parties such as copyright owners, internet service providers, wireless service providers and/or law enforcement agencies, including disclosing such information to third parties, all in our discretion. Such disclosures may be carried out without notice to you.

  4. Business Transfer

We may share your information, including your Personal Information, and Usage Information with our parent, subsidiaries and affiliates for internal reasons. We also reserve the right to disclose and transfer all such information: (i) to a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of the Services or applicable database; or (ii) in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of substantially all of our membership interests and/or assets or other corporate change, including, during the course of any due diligence process.

* What About Information I Disclose Publicly?

The Services may permit you to submit ideas, questions, comments, suggestions or other content, including Personal Information that is publicly viewable (such as on public portions of your user profile) (collectively, "User Content"). We or others may reproduce, publish, distribute or otherwise use User Content online or offline in any media or format (currently existing or hereafter developed). Others may have access to this User Content and may have the ability to share it with third parties across the Internet. Please think carefully before deciding what information you share, including Personal Information, in connection with your User Content.

Note that MyMoneyKarma does not control who will have access to the information that you choose to make public, and cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy or keep it secure. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any information that you disclose publicly or share with others, whether through the Services or otherwise. We are not responsible for the accuracy, use or misuse of any content or information that you disclose or receive through the Services.

* What About Security?

MyMoneyKarma maintains physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with regulations to protect Personal Information that we collect about you. We enable our servers with Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to establish a secure connection between your computer and our servers, creating a private session. We employ firewalls and other security technologies to protect our servers from external attack and securely store your Personal Information. We control access to this information via secure web pages, and limit access to only those employees or third parties on a need to know basis.

We test our systems regularly to insure that our security mechanisms are up to date. We incorporate commercially reasonable safeguards to help protect and secure your Personal Information and Credit Report Information. However, no data transmission over the Internet, wireless transmission or electronic storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Please note that we cannot ensure the security of any information you transmit to us you provide us with your information at your own risk

* How do I know about changes to the Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may change this Online Privacy Statement. The effective date of this statement, as indicated below, shows the last time this statement was revised or materially changed. Checking the effective date below allows you to determine whether there have been changes since the last time you reviewed the statement.

* How long do we retain your Information?

MyMoneyKarma will not retain your sensitive personal information for longer than is required for the purposes for which the information may lawfully be used or is otherwise required under any other law for the time being in force

* Grievance Officer

If you have any concern or grievance or want to address any discrepancy with respect to the processing of any of the information/data you provided to MyMoneyKarma, please contact our Grievance Officer (Mr. Saiprasad Jella) by email addressed to askus@mymoneykarma.com and we will study the matter and take such action as we deem appropriate under the circumstances in accordance with law.
